# Himanshu Grover

## **Software Engineer**

+91 8171626726 hunnygr96@gmail.com

### **About Me**

A passionate Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience in software designing & development. Currently, I'm working with a blockchain based startup company, ValidateMe. I have strong expertise in problem-solving interaction design & responsive web apps. I love the technology-driven around the computer, laptop & mobiles. I'm always very interested to learn new languages & technologies.

## Skills

- >> HTML, CSS
- ➤ JavaScript
- ➤ ReactJS
- ➤ Material UI
- > UI & UX
- ➤ Bootstrap
- > LESS & SASS
- ➤ NodeJS
- ➤ ExpressJS
- ➤ MongoDB
- > AWS
- ➤ DevOps Basics

## **Awards**

- Y Star Of The Year
- 🏆 The CodeMaster
- 🏆 Code Quality Award

### **Focus**

➤ To simplify the design & code.

## Quote

"The more you will deep dive, the more you will learn"

## **Experience**

## ValidateMe (Affidabile Solutions), Noida | July 2021 - Present

SDE-2 (UI)

- > Converted the product's web app into a responsive web app.
- > Developed a canva based certificate builder tool (FE & BE both).
- > Optimised the code and converted complex code into simple code.
- > Participated in product engineering.

#### Website Toolbox, Noida | August 2016 - July 2021

Web Designer

- > Developed a LESS based framework called WT-framework for theming.
- > Developed & launched several themes of the product (Forum).
- > Enhanced existing theme editor for dynamic customization in product design.
- > Interacted with several clients and done design customizations.
- > Designed problem-solving mockups for the enhancements of the products.
- > Fixed complex design issues of the live system.
- > Interacted with developers and provided design support.

### **Education**

### Indira Gandhi National Open University, New Delhi | 2016 - 2018

Bachelor of Computer Applications (Dropout)

## **Projects**

#### **ValidateMe**

> Hassle free, trackable, and credible credentials that increase website traffic.

#### **EduLocker**

> A wallet that saves all your tamper-proof and verifiable digital credentials for life.

#### **Forum**

> An intuitive platform for all kind of discussion.

#### **Certificate Builder**

> A drag-n-drop tool to design certificate and badges.